Peter Yoo

Los Angeles, CA | 818-903-6868 | petersyoox@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio | Twitter

Fullstack Developer

Since graduating General Assembly's Bootcamp at the end of July 2022, I independently started learning new languages, libraries, and frameworks such as TypeScript, NextJS, TailwindCSS, React Query, Zustand, Jest, and React Testing Library. I've also joined the Hack for LA organization that focuses on civic minded open source projects for the city of LA and an advanced React bootcamp. I've also been taking a data structures and algorithms Udemy course and practicing algorithm problems everyday. I'm steadily improving my skills and I've been loving it!

Technical & Interpersonal Skills

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, HTML5, CSS3

Libraries and Frameworks: ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Django, NextJS, jQuery, Tailwind, Jest, React Testing Library, Zustand, React Query, Redux

Databases and other: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, RESTful Routing, JSON, Figma, Postman, Docker

Interpersonal skills: Friendly, Modest, Collaborative, Proactive, Curious

Technical Projects

Finch Collector - GitHub | App - Python, JavaScript | Django, PostgreSQL, AWS, Materialize

An app that allows users to add finches, each added finch has a feeding time and seeds that they like.

- Built a full CRUD web app utilizing Django/JavaScript with PostgreSQL as a database.
- Implemented user authorization through Django.

Skate React - GitHub | App - JavaScript | ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Google Firebase

An e-commerce website for users to purchase custom made or pre-built skateboards.

- Headed the frontend direction and design as the lead frontend developer.
- Built a full CRUD web app utilizing the MERN stack.

Tteok Bowl - GitHub | App - JavaScript | jQuery, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, bcrypt

A food ordering app that allows users to create a custom or premade bowl of their favorite spicy Korean rice-cake snack.

- Built a full CRUD web app following RESTful routing in a MVC architecture.
- Tested all backend routes during development using Postman.

Experience

Octopus Japanese Restaurant, Server

Encino, CA, 01/2010 - 03/2020

Marvel Animation, Storyboard Artist

Burbank, CA, 02/2017 - 12/2018

- Created rough and final storyboards from a handed script for the Spider-Man cartoon show.
- Solved issues related to camera positioning, character acting, timing, and storytelling.
- When art assets weren't available, had to improvise by designing quick background sets and assets.

CHY Painting, Estimator

North Hills, CA, 03/2014 - 12/2016

- Handled all the estimates/invoices and emails with clients for a painting company.
- Created and managed file structures and templates for the estimates/invoices, went on job sites and talked to clients for estimations.

Education

General Assembly Remote, 04/2022 - 07/2022

Full-stack software engineering 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.